{
    "id": "977ac197c79b491e97acd46af074ab20",
    "title": "Color Idioms",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "584e235a886d49bba8d24b736a81d25d",
            "title": "Color Idioms",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Yesterday’s ……………………. was due to unexpected problems with electricity production.",
                    "description": "Black out: loss of electricity complete darkening of a room when lights are put out sudden loss of memory",
                    "answers": [
                        "black out",
                        "black off",
                        "black in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Susie will go ……………………….. with envy when she sees your new car.",
                    "description": "To go green with envy is to be very jealous of objects belonging to other people.",
                    "answers": [
                        "red",
                        "blue",
                        "green"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is not the kind of guy you can depend on when you are in trouble. He’s ……………………..",
                    "description": "Be yellow means be a coward.",
                    "answers": [
                        "white",
                        "black",
                        "yellow"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "A lot of people want to adopt babies. It is the ……………………….. tape that discourages them.",
                    "description": "Red tape = delay in public affairs because there is too much attention to rules.",
                    "answers": [
                        "red",
                        "black",
                        "dark"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "James was neither brilliant nor hardworking. His Dad always treated him like a ………………………….. sheep.",
                    "description": "Black sheep = person of bad character",
                    "answers": [
                        "red",
                        "white",
                        "black"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mr. Mathews is going to take over as the next chairman. Be sure to roll out the ………………………….. carpet when he arrives.",
                    "description": "Roll out the red carpet = Give the best treatment",
                    "answers": [
                        "blue",
                        "red",
                        "green"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They have just purchased a new home in the ………………………… belt.",
                    "description": "Green belt = the countryside around a city",
                    "answers": [
                        "blue",
                        "green",
                        "white"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The situation is not as ……………………….. as you think.",
                    "description": "Black and white = When something is black and white, it is clear, simple and understandable.",
                    "answers": [
                        "black",
                        "white",
                        "black and white"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I’m feeling rather …………………………… these days. Have you got something to cheer me up?",
                    "description": "To feel blue is to be depressed.",
                    "answers": [
                        "grey",
                        "blue",
                        "pink"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He had to tell a ……………………………. lie to escape his mother’s punishment.",
                    "description": "White lie = A small insignificant lie.",
                    "answers": [
                        "blue",
                        "white",
                        "black"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The civil authority has given the ………………………… light to the project.",
                    "description": "Give the green light = To give the green light is to approve a project.",
                    "answers": [
                        "green",
                        "blue",
                        "white"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}